Mitchell Sviridoff Papers 5247
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Mitchell Sviridoff Papers
1877-1958
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Sviridoff, Mitchell
5247
8 cubic feet
8 linear ft.
Correspondence, papers (documents), correspondence.
Correspondence, speeches and writings about Connecticut labor, economic and agricultural history.
5557165
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 07, 2005
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 22, 2017
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Connecticut -- Economic conditions; Connecticut -- Economic policy; Israel -- Foreign relations -- United States; Labor unions -- Mergers -- United States; Labor unions -- Organizing -- Connecticut; Workers' education -- United States; Sviridoff, Mitchell, 1918-
5557165
- Speeches, writings, and Correspondence (Box 1, Folder All)
  Scope and Contents
  re: Conn. Technology Sub Committee Education; Current Climate of Ind. Rel. in Conn.; Msgr. Donnelly Testimonial; Forand Bill; Ideal Labor Contract; Economic Workshop Comm.; AFL-CIO Merger in Conn.; Conn. Fed. of Labor Speech, 1951; Labor Offers Suggestions for 1952; Leadership-Negro Community; New Technology and the Humanities; Wages/Wage Stabilization; Objectives of Ind. Unions in L-M Relations; The States in the 60's-Can They Meet the Challenge; Taft-Hartley; Unemployment; Labor Trends, Labor Hopes. re: Israel trip, plans, itinerary, etc.; w/ Ralph Slovenko, Tulane Univ., Sch. of Law re: preparation of a paper by Sviridoff for conf. "Industrial Rights Under Coll. Agreement"; w/ Clark Kerr, Consultant (and others) Fund for the Republic re: Conference on current developments in coll. barg.; w/ Joseph Mire, Exec. Dir., NILE and Jack Barbash, Univ. of Wisconsin - routine corresp. and paper re: "What Responsibilities Do Union Officers Have in Politics" del. at Univ.of Minn. Ind. Rel Center Labor Conference; Speech notes and corresp. re Arbitration. Photos and biographical data dues slips (UAW)
- Tapes, phonograph records, articles, speeches (Box 2, Folder All)
- Materials (Box 3, Folder All)
  Program from "A Dinner in Honor of Sviridoff"; corresp., minutes and related material with Joint Council on Economic Education; Conn. Economic Planning and Development Comm. of the Conn. State Bd. of Education re labor education; Corresp., pamphlets, speeches re New Haven Redevelopment project; Speeches and corresp. re public education; Speeches and reports including Labor in Conn., Union Officers Repsonsibility in Politics; Labor's Public Responsibility in internal union affairs; Confidential results of an opinion survey in New Haven area
- Economy and history of the State. Agricultural History; Economic and Social Structure; wage data (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Ethnicity of Connecticut. Ethnic surveys. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Connecticut Labor Before 1850 (paper) (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Connecticut Labor, 1877-1914 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Immigration, Knights of Labor, Industrial Conflict, Conn. Fed. of Labor (papers)
- Miscellaneous: Hartford Labor History (Box 4, Folder 5)
  papers, briefs, reports, clippings, etc.
- Hartford Times clippings, 1915-1920 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Hartford Times clippings, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Hartford Times clippings, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Hartford Times clippings, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Hartford Times clippings, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Hartford Times clippings, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Hartford Times clippings, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Hartford Times clippings, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Hartford Times clippings, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Hartford Times clippings, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 14a)
- Hartford Daily Courant, 1913-1938 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Strikes, 1919-1935 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  clippings from Hartford Courant and Hartford Times
- Miscellaneous notes (Box 4, Folder 17)
  (handwritten) History, Ethnicity, etc.
- Individual Unions- before 1902 (Alphabetically by City) (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Individual Unions- histories (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Connecticut Valley Worker, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  Vol. 1, No.l, Feb. 22, 1921
- Connecticut Craftsman, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 20a)
  Sept. 1901
- Anthony Mukenna: Federal Writers Work Project, Research Report (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Labor Union Directory, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Political Handbills- Labor, Socialist Parties (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Poster on Immigrants, "Plymouth Rock and Ellis Island" (Box 4, Folder 24)
- List of Factories in Connecticut - Dept. of Factory Inspection, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, Newsletter, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Letters- City of Bridgeport; NYU (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Investigation into the Affairs of Local 937, UAW., 1950 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Conntcticut State CIO Yearbook, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 29-30)
- Connecticut State Labor Council Yearbook, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 31-32)
- Materials (Box 5, Folder All)
  Speech re: AFL-CIO Merger, union security, National Assn. of Manufacturers support of A. Stevenson in 1952, Bridgeport Brass Program, newspaper clippings; Corresp. from Walter Reuther re: United World Federalists and strengthening the UN, 2/22/51; Speech in support of J. Kennedy for Pres.; News releases by Gov. Bowles of Conn. ;Corresp. from Gov. Bowles to MS; Corresp. w/ Mayor Lee, New Haven re: city hiring non union personnel to clean the schools ;Corresp. (fan mail) re: paper entitled "Labor's Public Responsibility in Internal Union Affairs" by MS; Misc. corresp. including support for MS reappointment to the State Bd. of Mediation and Arbitration (CT)
- Materials (Box 6, Folder All)
  Conn. Economic Planning and Development Committee, Sub-Committee, New Technologies and Employment Opportunities (SM Chmn. of Sub-Committee) documentation includes analyses of issues and recommendations, notes, publications, meeting reports, agendas, etc.; Corresp. to Reuther and others reporting on events with Local 987, UAW; Corresp. and release in support of Sviridoff continuing as member of State Bd. of Mediation; And other miscellaneous
- Record lathe/dictation machine (Box 7)
- Images digitized from the collection. (Box 8)